どうしよう
あ  あの
Then is it me?
U-Um...
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www.Kamigami.org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 Syura 时间轴：小青
Wha-
What now?
Don't think about it.
考えるな
深く考えるな 霧島海人
Don't think too hard about it, Kirishima Kaito.
That wasn't a confession yesterday.
昨日は別に 先輩に告白したわけじゃない
She didn't even realize what I meant the day before.
一昨日のことだって 先輩は気づいてなかったじゃないか
平常心よ イチカ
Get a hold of yourself, Ichika.
I'm older than him. I have to keep my cool.
海人君より 年上の私がしっかりしなくちゃ
I'll just make him breakfast like always
いつものように 朝食を作って
and put a bit of effort into cooking up lunchboxes...
ちょっと 頑張って
お弁当なんかも作ってみたり
Yeah, nothing is weird about this.
そうさ なんの問題もない
この家に 先輩が同居しているってだけで
We're just sharing the house.
それだけで
Nothing else.
Just be yourself...
自然体よ イチカ
Just be yourself, Ichika. Like always.
あくまで自然体に
いつも通りに
平常心 平常心 平常心
Be cool. Be cool. Be cool.
私は やれば出来る子だから 自信持って
I can do so much. Working up some courage can't be hard.
Well, maybe I shouldn't put myself in such a great light...
いや 出来る子って変かな
Good morning!
むしろ
おはようございます
お おはよう
Good morning...
It's... such a lovely day!
い いい天気ですね
そうですね
Yeah...
There's hardly a cloud in the sky.
今日は 晴れますよ
Yeah...
そうですね
もうすぐ 期末テストです
Finals are coming up.
Yeah...
そうですね
勉強は苦手です
I'm bad at studying.
そうですか
Really?
I don't even remember what I had for breakfast...
朝 何食ったかも覚えてねえ
Good morning, Kirishima.
おはよう
霧島君
Normally you wake up later.
珍しく 早起きなんだね
It happens.
た たまにはね
ああ 谷川 昨日はごめん
Hey, Tanigawa. Sorry about yesterday.
We never met up again.
逸れたまま それきりになって
Don't apologize. It was my fault too.
ううん 私のほうこそごめんね
っていうか 檸檬先輩や美桜が悪い
Actually, it was all Lemon and Mio's fault.
I apologized yesterday...
昨日も散々謝った
Oh right, get this, Kaito.
そうだ 聞いてよ 海人君
昨日 檸檬先輩だけじゃなくて
Lemon is one thing, but Tetsuro and Mio were stalking me as well.
哲郎や美桜も私のこと覗いてたんだよ
Really?
ああ そうなの
Sorry, Kirishima...
ごめんなさい 霧島君
I don't mind.
いや 別に
Did something happen to you?
何かあったの
Something? What do you mean?
な 何かって何が
You're not your usual self.
いつもと態度が違うから
Really? I don't think so.
そ そ そうかな そんなことないよ
いたって普通だよ
I'm being perfectly normal!
I hear you were in Karuizawa yesterday.
昨日 軽井沢に行ったんですって
えっ まあ うん
Study  Time
Why?
何しに
I had a bit of shopping to do...
買い物をちょっと
Kirishima was there too.
霧島君もいたわ
軽井沢に
In Karuizawa.
Was he now?
そ そう
Kirishima.
霧島君 霧島君
Fascinating.
面白いわ
I bet she's uncomfortable now.
やっぱ 困らしちゃってんだよな
Not at all.
ううん そんなことない
It just caught me off guard.
突然だったから 動揺しただけなの
I actually like you too.
私だって 海人君のことが
Are you serious?!
マジっすか
You bet!
マジっすよ
Yay! It's mutual!
わい 両思いだ
I did it...
やった
I don't swing that way.
俺にそっちの趣味はねえ
That's how I should've reacted.
そりゃ俺のリアクションだ
Here.
ほら
弁当
A lunch box?
さっき イチカ先輩に頼まれたんだよ
Ichika asked me to give it to you.
海に 渡してくれって
She did?
先輩が
Don't forget it at home when she went
through the trouble of making it for you.
せっかく作ってくれたもん
忘れんなよ
Oh yeah...
ああ そうだよな
Hey, Tetsuro.
あのさ 哲郎
So, hypothetically speaking...
例え話なんだけどさ
Suppose that Mr. A confessed to Ms. B.
A男君がB子ちゃんに告白めいたことをした
I love you!
Moments later, Ms. B went home without saying a word.
直後 B子ちゃんは黙って帰ってしまった
I love you!
Since then, Ms. B has been really awkward around Mr. A.
それ以降 A男君に対するB子ちゃんの態度が
どうにもぎこちない
What do you think Ms. B is thinking?
B子ちゃんの心理状態を答えよ
困ってんじゃねえ
She's uncomfortable?
だよな
Thought so.
Suppose that Mr. B confessed to Ms. A.
A美ちゃんはB太君に 告白めいたことをされ
She was so surprised that she just left.
あまりの驚きに その場から逃げ出してしまいました
So the question is, "How should Ms. A act?"
ここで クエスチョン
A美ちゃんがとるべき態度とは
She should tell him how she feels.
返事をするべきね
Thought so.
そうだね
ちなみに A美ちゃんはB太君のことをどう思っているの
So how does Ms. A feel about Mr. B?
決して嫌っているわけではありません
She doesn't dislike him at all.
She thinks he's cute.
可愛いとさえ思っているようです
Then why not go out with him?
なら オーケーすれば
It's not that simple.
問題はそう簡単ではありません
Why?
なぜ
それは
Because Ms. A will...
A美ちゃんが
いずれ この町を離れてしまうからです
eventually have to leave the city.
Ms. B is definitely uncomfortable,
B子ちゃんは確かに困ってる
but I have no idea whether she wishes it'd all go away, or she just doesn't know what to do.
けど 迷惑に感じてるのか
ただ単に困惑してるだけなのか 分かんねえし
A男君は 結果を焦らないほうがいいと思うぜ
I think it'd be best if Mr. A didn't rush things.
焦るな か
Not rush things, huh?
サボり魔 発見
I spy a little slacker.
あ 谷川
Hey, Tanigawa.
What is it? You tired?
何 疲れちゃった
Yeah, a little.
ちょっとな
Hey, you never finished telling me what happened to you yesterday.
あのさ 今朝 聞きそびれちゃったんだけど
昨日 逸れたあと
So what did you do afterward?
何してた
I got bored and went home.
ああ しかたなく 家に戻ったけど
I see.
そっか
悪い
Sorry.
探してくれた
Did you go looking for me?
あら 霧島君と谷川さんじゃない
Well, if it isn't Kirishima and Tanigawa.
なんだ 檸檬先輩か
Oh, it's just you, Lemon.
That's quite the greeting.
ご挨拶ね
魅力的な年上の女性が
Do you have nothing else to say about an attractive upperclassmen and her alluring swimsuit-clad body?
妖艶な水着姿を晒しているというのに
Alluring?
妖艶って
It's just a normal school swimsuit.
ただのスク水ですけど
Lemon,
檸檬 集合だって
we're supposed to assemble...
い 行きましょう 檸檬
Let's go, Lemon.
Okay.
A美ちゃんには C子ちゃんってライバルがいるみたいね
It would seem that Ms. A has a rival called Ms. C.
えっ なんのこと
What are you talking about?
Are things still pretty awkward between you two?
もしかして まだ貴月先輩とギクシャクしてるの
Yeah, kinda.
ああ まあ
You need to pull yourself together!
海人君 しっかりしなきゃ
Huh?
She's isn't from this country,
そりゃ 貴月先輩は外国の人だから
so she might be having trouble communicating or something.
コミニケーションとか
いろいろと問題があるかもしれない
でもね 先輩は一人でこの国に来て
And since she came here all alone,
she just might be feeling scared or lonely.
不安だったり 寂しい思いをしてるんじゃないかな
You should be there to support her as best you can.
そこは 海人君がフォローしてあげないと
ああ そうだな
Yeah, I guess.
うん 谷川の言う通りだと思う
I think you're right.
I've only been thinking about myself.
俺 自分のことばっか考えてた
それじゃ だめだよな
That was pretty selfish.
But it's good that you think about others' feelings.
けど 相手の人のことをちゃんと考える海人君はいいと思うよ
Thanks.
ありがとう
Good luck.
頑張れ
Sure.
Oh man, Ms. C over there just shot herself in the foot.
わあ C子ちゃん 地雷踏みっぱなしだよ
Ms. C?
C子ちゃん
しっかりしなきゃ しっかり
I have to get my act together.
I have to.
イチカ先輩
Ichika!
な 何かしら
What is it?
昨日のことなんですけど
About what happened yesterday...
I'm sorry I acted the way I did.
俺 変な態度取っちゃって すみません
でも そういう意味じゃないですから
But that's not what I meant back there.
Don't worry about it.
気にしないでください
Oh, I understand!
そうだったんだ
だから 普段通りで行きましょう
So let's pretend it never happened!
It never happened!
普段通りにする
よし これだ
That's it!
With that, things'll be back to normal!
このパタンで現状を打破する
I can do it!
俺はやれる やるんだ やらなくちゃ
I'll do it!
I have to do it!
やりたい
I want to do it!
Are you that horny?
そんなに堪ってんの
Of course!
ええ そりゃもう
で えっ 真 真奈美さん
Ma-Manami?
Let me help you with that.
なんなら あたしが相手してあげようか
With what?
なんのです
Use your imagination.
I don't get it.
意味分かんない
Oh, don't feign innocence.
純情ぶっちゃって
まあいいか
Well, whatever.
Kai, I'm going shopping.
海 あたし買い物の途中なの
Come with me!
付き合ってよ
I don't have a choice, do I?
反論なし でしょう
ご明察
Nope.
Kaito, I was really happy to hear how you felt about me.
海人君
海人君の気持ちはとっても嬉しかった
But we just met,
でも 私たちは まだ 出会ったばっかりで
so could you give me some time?
だから お返事は少し時間をもらえないかな
I'll give it some thought before giving you my answer.
海人君のことをよく考えて ちゃんと返事します
Let's act like normal until then.
それまでは いつも通りでいましょう
Yes. I understand.
はい 分かりました 先輩の言うことに従います
I will do as you say.
うん こんな感じで話せば
Piece of cake!
海人君
Kaito?
Who's that woman?
あの女性は
Wh-What's going on?
ど どういうこと
But yesterday he said...
昨日は私に
そりゃ ちゃんと返事をしなかった私もいけないけど
I mean, it's my fault for not giving him my answer yet, but...
it hasn't even been a day, and he's already on a date with another woman?
昨日の今日で もう違う女の人とデートしてるのなんて
I don't believe this!
信じられない
I was stupid for even worrying about this!
悩んでいた私がバカみたいじゃない
I don't care what you do!
もう 勝手にすればいいわ
りのん リンゲージで私をシャンプさせて
Rinon.
Let me jump with the quantum link.
If you bail on me again, you're going into the stew.
今日こそ応答してくれないと どうなるか分からないわよ
りのん これは あれなの
Rinon, we're doing this only because Sistersis asked me to take care of Kaito.
お姉ちゃんさんに 海人君のことを頼まれたから
よろしくねって言われたから
She left him in my care.
That's it. That's all there is to this.
それだけ それだけなんだから
You Were Amazing.
Episode Four
This and this. And this too.
これとこれ ああ これも
You're buying a lot.
そんなに買うの
It's a real fight this time.
今回は長期戦だから
I see.
そうですか
で 次はどこ行くんです
So, where to next?
ちょ 真奈美さん
Manami?
嬉しいくせに
I know you like it.
Don't be ridiculous!
あ あんなに大胆に
They're walking around like that?!
ここは
What is this...
Hey, are you done yet?
あの まだですか
Kai, wanna check it out?
海 見たい
I'm good!
いいですよ
What's your opinion?
どう 似合う
It's a perfect fit!
ええ もう ばっちりですよ
Just buy it already!
だから と とと とっとと買っちゃってください
No way...
そんな
海人君
Kaito...
海人 こっちにいらっしゃい
Come over here, Kaito.
Okay...
はい
You're a good boy.
いい子ね
どう イチカって子より 私のほうが全然いいでしょう
What do you think?
I'm way better than that Ichika girl, don't you think?
Of course.
もちろんです
She didn't even bother giving you an answer.
告っても 返事もしてくれない女のことなんか 忘れちゃいなさい
Just forget about her.
Okay...
はい
りのん
Rinon!
I'll take a quick shower.
あたし シャワー浴びるから
勝手にお茶でも飲んでて
Make yourself some tea or something.
Sure...
Kai!
海 一緒に入る
Wanna take one with me?
心より遠慮します
I'm afraid I must decline.
可愛くないわね
You're not cute at all.
Man...
I have to talk to her when I get back.
帰ったら 先輩に言わないとな
About what?
何を
せ 先輩
Huh? Why are you...
どうして
That doesn't matter.
そんなことはどうでもいいの
But...
だって
帰るわよ
We're going home.
Huh? Why?
なんで
I said we're going home.
いいから 帰るの
ちょっ ちょっと 待ってくださいよ
Wait a second.
そんなにここにいたいの
Do you want to stay here that badly?
で でも 挨拶ぐらいは
But...
I should at least say goodbye.
You okay?
先輩
バカ
You jerk!
Why?
どうして どうして
Why am I...
なんで 私 こんなに
あのう 先輩 なんか 誤解して
Uh... Hey, are you...
What's going on out here?
何バタバタしてんの
誰 この子
Huh? Who's she?
もしかして 海の
Maybe your girlfr—
No!
違う（違います）
じゃあ 何
Then?
Sistersis asked me to take care of Kaito.
わ 私は お姉ちゃんさんから 海人君のことを頼まれているものです
七海から
Nanami did?
そうです ですから
Yes.
That's why I can't allow him to stay here.
ここに 海人君をいさせるわけにはいきません
You've got...
先輩 あの
Kaito, you shut up.
海人君は黙ってて
Sorry.
すみません
うん いいじゃない 恋愛は自由よ
What's the fuss? Love is free.
You seem a lot older.
随分と年上のようですけど
歳の差なんて 関係ないわ
Age doesn't matter.
Kaito is in high school!
海人君は高校生です
Love overcomes all obstacles.
愛に障害はつきものよ
Manami, what are you talking...
真奈美さん 何を言って
Kaito, you shut up!
海人君は黙ってて
Sorry.
すみません
You don't get it?
分からない
What?
何がですか
お邪魔なの
You're getting in his way.
私は海人君を守る義務があるんです
I have a duty to protect Kaito.
それだけ
That's all?
それだけの理由で 他人の家に断りもなく 上がりこんできたわけ
That's why you came into someone else's house without permission?
Was I not supposed to?
い 行けませんか
It's pretty odd.
非常識よ
いい加減白状したら
Why not just say it already?
ここに来た本当の理由を
The real reason you came here.
There's no other reason.
そんなの ありません
本当に
Oh really?
ありません
Yeah really!
海 この子 相当鈍いわよ
Kai, this girl is pretty dim.
What do you mean?
何が
お前もか
You too?
Oh, just do whatever you want then.
ああ もう勝手にすればいいわ
そういうのも 楽しい時期だろうし
I suppose that's fun at your age.
Sis?
姉ちゃん なんだよ また来たのかよ
You're back?
お 姉さん
Sister?
あれ 海 イチカ先輩まで
Oh? Kai? Ichika?
You brought them here?
姉ちゃんが連れてきたの
Kinda.
まあ そんなところ
じゃ まあ ゆっくりしててよ
Well, make yourselves at home.
つうか そんな格好してんなよ
Don't just stand there like that.
Put on some clothes.
着替えろって
Fine, fine.
分かった 分かった
石垣君 あの お姉さんって
Ishigaki... your sister...
紹介まだなんですか
She didn't introduce herself?
あれ 俺のお姉ちゃん 小倉真奈美です
She's my sister. Ogura Manami.
Ogura? She's got a different name.
小倉 苗字が
結婚してますから
She's married.
But whenever they fight she comes back here to mope.
っていうか 姉ちゃん 旦那と喧嘩するたびに
すぐこっち戻ってきてグチグチするんですよ
今回ばかり許さないわ
I'm not gonna forgive him this time!
喧嘩の理由は
What happened?
He erased the show I recorded!
あの人 あたしが録画した番組 勝手に消したの
You can't be serious.
うわ くだんねえ
楽しみにしてたのよ
I was really looking forward to watching it!
Who cares? Go back to Satoshi's place already.
いいから さとしさんとこ戻れよ
No apologies will do this time!
土下座したって許さない
Just forget about it!
許せよ
I've run out of patience this time!
今回という今回は ホントに愛想が尽きたわ
Please don't!
尽きるなよ
Whose side are you on?!
あんたはどっちの見方よ
The right side!
正義だよ
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい ホントにごめんなさい
I'm really sorry!
Really, it's fine.
あいや 大丈夫ですよ
I'm sorry I made you worry.
というか 心配かけて こっちこそ すみません
It was all my fault.
全面的に私が悪いです
真奈美さんが誤解させるようなこというから 仕方ないですよ
Manami was being misleading on purpose,
so it's not your fault.
Let's just go.
さあ 行きましょう
Hey, Kaito.
ねえ 海人君 お詫びをさせて
Let me make it up to you.
何でもするから
I'll do anything.
何でも
Anything?
ええ 何でも
Anything.
I really wanted to
あの時 僕は
本当は聞きたかったんだ
ask her then.
I wanted to ask her how she feels about me.
昨日の返事を
僕のことをどう思っているのか
でも
But...
俺 勉強を苦手なんです
I'm bad at studying.
先輩 教えてもらえませんか
Could you help me out?
うん 頑張る
I'll do what I can!
You misspelled it there. That's not an "e," but an "i."
そこのスペル間違ってるわよ
そこは 「E」じゃなくて 「I」です
すみません
Sorry.
Math is up after English.
英語が終わったら 次は数学ね
Shouldn't we get some sleep, Ichika?
先輩 もう 寝ませんか 明日も学校あるし
We have school tomorrow.
We don't have much time until finals.
期末テストまで 時間がないのよ
With these grades, I can understand why Sistersis was worried about you!
こんな学力じゃ
お姉ちゃんさんも心配するわ
せめて平均点以上を目指さないと
We need to at least get you above average.
赤点じゃなきゃいいですよ
It doesn't matter as long as I don't fail.
That's the wrong attitude!
そういう態度だから ダメなの
You asked me to help you with your studies, didn't you?
勉強教えてほしいって言ったの 海人君でしょう
I did.
はい
はい 問題解いて
Now solve this problem.
I shouldn't've said anything...
言わなきゃよかった
おい 海 大丈夫か
Hey, Kai. Are you okay?
パイが
-chik...
あ おっぱい
Chicks?
Ichika has a side I didn't know.
先輩が ああいう性格だと思わなかった
Kaito!
海人君 勉強するわよ
Time to study!
Takatsuki?
貴月先輩
But... it's lunch break...
先輩 今はお昼休み
Read the book while you eat then!
食べながら勉強よ 時間がないの
Time is running out!
あ はい
R-Right.
ああ 大変そう
Poor Kai...
I'm glad, though.
でも よかった
何が
Why?
海人君と貴月先輩がギクシャクしなくなって
Kaito and Takatsuki made up.
うん よかった
That's good.
C子ちゃんは鈍かった
Ms. C isn't the sharpest tool in the shed.
何するのよ
What are you doing?!
もう 女の子の頭に軽々しく触るな
Don't just touch a girl's head out of the blue!
A girl?
女の子 ほう 女の子
You, a girl?
What the heck? Try saying that again!
何よ もう一回言ってみなさいよ
Final Exams
Math I
English
Chinese Literature
Closing Ceremony
Start
海人君
Kaito!
Oh hey!
先輩
Let's go home.
帰ろ
夏休みが 始まろうとしていた
Summer vacation was just around the corner.
一生 忘れられることのない
It was going to be a summer I'd never...
忘れられない 夏
...ever forget.
きっとそれは
I'm sure...
皆も同じだったと思う
...everyone else felt the same way.
喜びや 悲しみ 痛み
Happiness, sadness, and pain...
All of that put together in one package.
そういうのを 全部ひっくるめて
たった一度の
A once-in-a-lifetime experience...
あの夏が始まる
The summer we've been waiting for...
You are the lead.
Episode Five
I found out Ichika's true identity!
Don't tell anyone, or I'll...
Tetsuro is dead!
イチカ先輩の正体
見切った
言わないで そうでないと 私は
哲郎君が 死んじゃった